Hello, all my friends, and welcome to exercise number 29.
We are asked to ride the program to calculate the average value of array elements, so both the video
and think about the algorithm, how to write the algorithm of this exercise that get the value of array
of elements and make the average based on their length or their number.
So I'm waiting your comments in the link below and the description below, so I need from you to make
this program and write them down.
So let's go to that idea and start making and thinking about this product.
So I will solve it in a Java, because it's fairly common with C and C++ and and also common with Python,
so I'm I'm learning and teaching you and this course, the algorithm, I'm not me and not teaching you
this syntax.
If you want the syntax, we have many courses that teaches you a Java, Kotlin, Android and so on.
So what we will do in order to calculate the average of an array.
Think about like 10 numbers.
This array contains 10 numbers.
I need to get all the values of these 10 numbers and divide them by 10 because they are the length or
the element.
Number of these elements is 10.
So how to do that?
Let's think about and array called numbers OK, equal to new end end array.
And this entry contains like.
The grades of mathematical, mathematical class, math class.
12, four, 13, 14, seven, 16, 13, 11.
This are six students, OK now.
The first step is to calculate the sum of all Adelaide elements.
I will create and sum equal to zero the start there was the song.
OK, so we need the first step.
I will mark them here.
First step.
I love comments because if you need that course, this that to ride the course or to read it, to write
the exercises or to solve exercises.
Also, you need to make and segment old and partition all the steps correctly.
And also, if you need to revise them for the exam or to interview, you know what we have done.
OK?
Despite spending many time and many hours like thinking what we have done, why we are using the summer,
because we need to make this sum and then divide them over that length of the array, it's very simple.
OK.
For I will start for I told you that when you see an array, think about using the loops because we
need to traverse through the array elements while PN numbers dot length and I plus plus OK, I need
to get the some the previous that a new sum equal to that old.
Some last numbers at I.
OK.
And this way I am getting the sum of all the elements right elements and stored it inside the sun.
So the first step here we are getting the summation of all of these elements.
OK.
So let me try to solve it with mathematics.
12 plus 13 plus 14 plus 16 plus 13 plus 11 equals 17.
79.
OK, now some is equal to 79.
The second step is calculating that average.
Then, you know, from mathematics, like the average of the sum, the sum of all elements is divided
by number of elements.
So we have one, two, three, four, five and six.
So if we divide seven nine.
Sorry.
79 divided by six.
This is the average, it's thirteen point sixteen.
OK, we are dividing them by the number of the elements.
So for that, we need to create a double because the average would be afloat some over.
What is the number of are number?
Are these numbers raise?
It's a six.
But this is this isn't the case.
We know the numbers.
Length.
OK, so these are the number six, but if I don't know their numbers, if I create an array like 100.
No, and I tell a the user to enter what he what he want from the numbers he entered like 10 numbers.
So the length it will not be 100, it would be 10.
So in this case, the dynamics of dynamic length of the array depends on the number of the elements.
So it would be solving the problem by using no dog length.
This is why we use the average the sum.
Over the numbers, though, at length.
Now let's a print system that's print on the screen there or in the console.
The result?
So since them got out that print average value of the array.
Is everything OK, let's run and see.
And the average value of the array is is thirteen point zero.
It's very good.
OK.
We are dividing the sum over the length of the.
Let me check again the some.
And here we go, it's about 30.
OK.
But there is a problem here.
If we run it again, we see that the average is 13 one zero.
It's not displaying the decimal part.
So we need to make light to cast it, to double here, just casting it and let's run again.
And here we go.
We have thirteen point sixty six nine six two six six six.
OK.
So it's very simple.
This is the algorithm of how to make a program that calculate the average value of element.
Of their.